Their innocence. Their heritage. Their lives.
Glory is a drama, history, war film directed by Edward Zwick.
Robert Gould Shaw leads the US Civil War's first all-black volunteer company,
fighting prejudices of both his own Union army and the Confederates.
Col. Robert Gould Shaw, played by Matthew Broderick.
Pvt. Trip, played by Denzel Washington.
Maj. Cabot Forbes, played by Cary Elwes.
Sgt. Maj. John Rawlins, played by Morgan Freeman.
Pvt. Jupiter Sharts, played by Jihmi Kennedy.
Cpl. Thomas Searles, played by Andre Braugher.
Glory is a 1989 American epic historical war drama film directed by Edward Zwick about the 54th Massachusetts
Infantry Regiment, one of the Union Army's earliest African American regiments in the American Civil War.
It stars Matthew Broderick as Colonel Robert Gould Shaw, the regiment's commanding officer, and
Denzel Washington, Cary Elwes, and Morgan Freeman as fictional members of the 54th.
The screenplay by Kevin Jarre was based on the books Lay This Laurel (1973) by Lincoln Kirstein
and One Gallant Rush (1965) by Peter Burchard and the personal letters of Shaw.
The film depicts the soldiers of the 54th from the formation of their regiment
to their heroic actions at the Second Battle of Fort Wagner.
Glory was co-produced by Tri-Star Pictures and Freddie Fields Productions,
and distributed by Tri-Star Pictures in the United States.
It premiered in limited release in the United States on December 15, 1989, and in wide release
on February 16, 1990, grossing $27 million worldwide on an $18 million budget.
The film was nominated for five Academy Awards and won three, with Washington winning Best Supporting Actor in addition to
receiving the corresponding Golden Globe, while Freddie Francis was nominated for the BAFTA Award for Best Cinematography.
The film won awards from the Kansas City Film Critics Circle, the
Political Film Society, and the NAACP Image Awards.
The film explores themes of based on true story, racism,
battle, union soldier, confederate soldier.
The tone is emotional.